Guide to the Dan Laurence papers, circa 1950-2006
Laurence, Dan papers, circa 1950-2006
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dan Laurence papers, circa 1950-2006
4662
Dan H. Laurence
31.5 cubic feet
Typewritten transcripts, photocopies, and microfilm of letters and manuscripts; page proofs and galley proofs..
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists mainly of typewritten transcripts of letters by George Bernard Shaw, eventually published in the edition of Shaw's collected letters edited by Dan Laurence. With the transcripts are some notes, photocopies and microfilm of Shaw letters and manuscripts, and page proofs and galley proofs for the Collected letters. Also included is Dan Laurence's personal correspondence from 2002-2005.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Dan H. Laurence was born Daniel Hyman Goldstein on March 28, 1920, in the Bronx. He changed his name in 1946. A noted scholar, editor, and bibliographer who taught at a number of different universities over the course of his career, Laurence devoted most of his professional life to the works of George Bernard Shaw. He compiled a two-volume bibliography of Shaw's works, and edited Shaw's collected letters, collected plays, music criticism, prefaces, and unpublished writings. Laurence died on February 5, 2008, in San Antonio, Texas, at the age of 87.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists mainly of typewritten transcripts of letters by Bernard Shaw, eventually published in the edition of Shaw's collected letters edited by Dan Laurence. With the transcripts are some notes, photocopies and microfilm of Shaw letters and manuscripts, and page proofs and galley proofs for the Collected letters. Also included is Dan Laurence's personal correspondence from 2002-2006.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Laurence, Dan H.; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950--Correspondence.; Laurence, Dan H.
Subjects:
Editors.; Editing.
Form and Genre Terms:
Manuscripts for publication.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Bernard F. Burgunder Collection of George Bernard Shaw, #4617.
Related books formerly owned by Dan Laurence are cataloged individually.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Typewritten transcripts and photocopies of letters by Bernard Shaw
  NOTE: Dates in this series are the dates of the original letters, not the dates when the transcripts were made.
  - Transcripts of letters, with one photograph of some of the originals, 1874-1890 (Box 1)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1891-1896 (Box 2)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1897-June 1900 (Box 3)
  - Transcripts of letters, July 1900-1902 (Box 4)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1903 (Box 5)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1904-June 1905 (Box 6)
  - Transcripts of letters, July 1905-1906 (Box 7)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1907 (Box 8)
  - Transcripts of letters, January-August 1908 (Box 9)
  - Transcripts of letters, September 1908-1909 (Box 10)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1910-March 1911 (Box 11)
  - Transcripts of letters, April-December 1911 (Box 12)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1912 (Box 13)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1913 (Box 14)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1914-1915 (Box 15)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1916-June 1917 (Box 16)
  - Transcripts of letters, July 1917-1918 (Box 17)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1919-1920 (Box 18)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1921-1922 (Box 19)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1923-1924 (Box 20)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1925-1927 (Box 21)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1928-1930 (Box 22)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1931-1933 (Box 23)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1934-1936 (Box 24)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1937-1939 (Box 25)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1940-1942 (Box 26)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1943-1945 (Box 27)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1946-1948 (Box 28)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1949-1950 (Box 29)
  - Transcripts of letters (undated); transcripts of letters to Augustin Hamon; letters from Charlotte Shaw, Undated; 1909-1914; 1901?-1907 (Box 31)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1940-1950 (Box 32)
  - Transcripts of letters, unsorted, Various dates (Box 39)
  - Transcripts of letters for Collected Letters volume 3, 1911-1925 (Box 40)
  - Transcripts of letters for Collected Letters, unsorted, Various dates (Box 41)
- Series II. Galleys, page proofs, and research materials for Collected Letters
  - Page proofs for Collected Letters, volume 4 (1926-1950) (Box 30)
  - Page proofs for Collected Letters, volume 1 (1874-1897); notes (Box 33)
  - Page proofs for Collected Letters, volume 4 (1926-1950) (Box 30)
  - Galleys, typescript, etc. for Collected Letters, volume 2 (1898-1910); miscellaneous transcripts and photocopies of correspondence for various volumes of the work (Box 34)
  - Galleys, typescript, etc. for Collected Letters, volume 4 (1926-1950) (Box 35)
  - Microfilm of: Shaw's address book, manuscripts (Passion Play, Gadfly, etc.), and letters held at various libraries and museums (Box 36)
  - Film negatives of Shaw's correspondence with Augustin and Henriette Hamon; microfilm of Shaw diaries; typewritten transcripts of Shaw's letters to Marie Stopes, 1916-1949; notes on the book Florence Farr, Bernard Shaw, W.B. Yeats Letters, edited by Clifford Bax (London, 1946), with the book (Box 37)
  - Notes, page proofs, and typewritten transcripts of letters for Collected Letters, volume 2 (1898-1910) (Box 38)
- Series III. Dan Laurence personal correspondence
  - Letters to and from Dan Laurence, 2002-2006 (Box 42)